Elizabeth P. Richardson Papers, 1865-1998
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
Elizabeth P. Richardson Papers
1865-1998
Richardson, Elizabeth P., 1922-1998
7
50 boxes (15 linear ft.)
Mortimer Rare Book Room Smith College Northampton, MA
Editor and serious collector of the work of the Bloomsbury Group, Virginia Woolf, and other associated with her. Includes correspondence, a collection of scrapbooks containing articles and images related to Virginia Woolf and the Bloomsbury Group, reading notes, drafts of essays, notes and galley proofs for Richardson's A Bloomsbury Iconography, and artwork.
Elizabeth Power Richardson was born on August 28, 1922 in Newton, Massachusetts. She attended Smith College, graduating in 1943. Elizabeth Power Richardson was the supervising editor at McGraw Hill College Division, specializing in the physical sciences. She continued to work as a freelance editor after she married American Foreign Service officer W. Garland Richardson in 1949.
Richardson's interest in Virginia Woolf began at the age of twelve, when she first heard Flush read out loud. She began collecting articles for her Virginia Woolf scrapbooks in the early 1940s, with the idea of creating a book that would track the fluctuation in Woolf's reputation. Although this project was abandoned, Richardson's interest in Woolf continued as she accompanied her husband abroad to countries such as Suriname and Japan. Unfortunately, her first library of early editions of Virginia Woolf was dropped into Yokohama Harbor by mistake en route from Monrovia, Liberia, to Tokyo. But Mrs. Richardson continued to collect, expanding her collection to include members of the Bloomsbury Group and others associated with Virginia Woolf. Over the years her "working collection" grew to include nearly two thousand volumes along with numerous scrapbooks of ephemera. Richardson was inspired by Roger Fry's statement that "the really useful collector [is one] who by merely bringing objects together, classifying them, interpreting their interrelationships creates new values altogether."1
While living in Suriname, Mrs. Richardson began creating illustration lists for the books in her collection and continued to do so after her return to the United States. Indexing photographic reproductions of the Bloomsbury Group became a passion, which eventually resulted in Mrs. Richardson's meticulously researched publication A Bloomsbury Iconography (Winchester: St. Paul's Bibliographies, 1989). Soon after her bibliography was published, she moved from her home in Geneva, New York, to Northampton, Massachusetts. In 1985, Elizabeth Richardson presented to Smith College a photograph album compiled by Leslie Stephen in 1895. Mrs. Richardson's children presented their mother's Bloomsbury Iconography Collection to the Mortimer Rare Book Room after her death in 1998.
1 Richardson, Elizabeth P. A Bloomsbury Iconography. Preface. St Paul's Bibliographies, 1989.
The Elizabeth P. Richardson Papers consist of 15 linear feet of material, dating from 1865 to 1998. Types of materials include correspondence, a collection of scrapbooks containing articles and images related to Virginia Woolf and the Bloomsbury Group, reading notes, drafts of essays, notes and galley proofs for Richardson's A Bloomsbury Iconography, and artwork. This collection was assembled by Elizabeth Power Richardson and donated to Smith College in 1998. Original correspondence from Elizabeth Richardson was donated by Panthea Reid and J. Howard Woolmer. Tony Bradshaw donated letters written to Barbara Strachey. The papers are arranged in six series.
This collection is organized into six series:
I. Correspondence of Elizabeth P. Richardson, 1961-1998
II. Scrapbooks, 1905-1998
III. Personal Papers, 1963-199?
IV. Subject Files, 1865-1997
V. A Bloomsbury Iconography, 1979-199?
VI. Oversize
The papers are arranged in six series.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The Elizabeth P. Richardson Papers are the physical property of the Mortimer Rare Book Room, Smith College. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors of works or their legal representatives.
History of the Collection
This collection was assembled by Elizabeth Power Richardson and donated to Smith College in 1998. Original correspondence from Elizabeth Richardson was donated by Panthea Reid and J. Howard Woolmer. Tony Bradshaw donated letters written to Barbara Strachey.
Search Terms
Richardson, Elizabeth P.; Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941.; Bloomsbury group.; Novelists, English--20th century.; Women novelists, English--20th century.; Bell, Quentin.; Bell, Anne Olivier.; Bicknell, John W., 1913-; Boyd, Elizabeth French, 1905-; Kirkpatrick, B. J. (Brownlee Jean); Reid, Panthea.; Rosenbaum, S. P. (Stanford Patrick), 1929-; Spotts, Frederic.; Strachey, Barbara, 1912-; Woolmer, J. Howard.
Additional Information
Related Material
In 1985, Elizabeth Richardson presented to Smith College a photograph album compiled by Leslie Stephen in 1895.
- Series I. Correspondence of Elizabeth P. Richardson, 1961-1998, 1.5 linear feet
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  This series includes correspondence relating to Richardson's book A Bloomsbury Iconography. Correspondents include museums, libraries, publishers, and Woolf scholars and authors, such as Joanne Trautmann Banks, John Bicknell, Elizabeth French Boyd, Angelica Garnett, Diane Gillespie, B. J. Kirkpatrick, Panthea Reid, S. P. Rosenbaum, Richard Shone, and Barbara Strachey. Particularly extensive is Richardson's correspondence with Quentin and Anne Olivier Bell, Leonard Woolf scholar Frederic Spotts, and J. Howard Woolmer, bookseller and author of A Checklist of the Hogarth Press, 1917-1938. A folder of permission letters for A Bloomsbury Iconography (Box 4, folder 128) completes the series.
- Series II. Scrapbooks, 1905-1998, 7.5 linear feet
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series consists of thirty-two scrapbooks compiled by Elizabeth P. Richardson. The scrapbooks include clippings and photocopies of articles and reviews of works by and about Virginia Woolf (Boxes 5-9, 30), articles about the Bloomsbury Group (Box 10), and articles about peripherary figures, such as Julia Margaret Cameron (Box 29). Also included are photocopies of dust jackets, photocopies of obituaries, indexes Richardson created for books related to Bloomsbury, and ephemera.
- Series III. Personal Papers, 1963-1998, 1.5 linear feet
  This series consists of seven reading notebooks, loose notes on photographs of the Bloomsbury Group, and drafts of Richardson's writings, excluding A Bloomsbury Iconography. Also included is the Ribblesdale Lear Scrapbook, in which Elizabeth P. Richardson presents her research on the copy of Edward Lear's Book of Nonsense owned by Thomas Lister, fourth Baron Ribblesdale (Mortimer Rare Book Room 825 L47b 1889). The Ribblesdale family used this book as a guest book, encouraging family and friends, such as John Singer Sargent, to color the illustrations (Box 36). Two audio recordings are also included in this series: one in which Richardson reads Moments of Being by Virginia Woolf and another entitled "A taste of green olives" (Box 38) in which Richardson discusses her Bloomsbury collection and her interest in Virginia Woolf.
- Series IV. Subject Files, 1865-1997, 1.25 linear feet
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series consists of nineteen items, including photocopies of novels, articles, and essays related to the Bloomsbury Group. Also included is a video recording of a performance of A Room of One's Own by Eileen Atkins (Box 41, Folder 166) and a T-shirt featuring a caricature of Woolf.
- Series V. A Bloomsbury Iconography, [1979]-[1991], 2 linear feet (10 items)
  This series consists of working papers for Elizabeth P. Richardson's A Bloomsbury Iconography. The series includes a fragment of an early draft composed in 1979 (Box 42, Folder 167), two later drafts, and corrected galley proofs. Also included are illustrative material, including original sketches by Sarah Black for Appendix A (Box 44, Folder 180), and a typescript of A Bloomsbury Iconography (Boxes 46-47).
- Series VI. Artwork, 1923-1996, .5 linear feet ( 4 items)
  Arranged alphabetically by artist.
- Series VII. Oversize, .75 linear feet (16 items)
- Series I. Correspondence of Elizabeth P. Richardson, 1961-1998
  Asterisks denote significant correspondence.
  - Alex Reid and Lefévre Ltd. 1984 Dec 26-1985 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allen Memorial Art Museum 1989 Aug 7-Aug 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annan, Noel Gilroy 1984 Jul 2-1984 Jul 18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Art Institute of Chicago 1984 Sep 14-Oct 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ashmolean Museum 1990 Jan 19-Feb 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bachardy, Don 1984 Dec 28-1989 Jul 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - *Banks, Joanne Trautmann 1985 Nov 22-1996 Jul 24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - BBC Hulton Picture Library 1983 Aug 18-1984 Apr 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bedford, Sue 1997 Sep 22-1997 Oct 4 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - *Bell, Quentin and Anne Olivier 1976 Jul 19-1997 Feb 22 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Berg Collection 1982 Nov 20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bethe, Rose Ewald 1979 Dec 15 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - *Bicknell, John W. 1983 Nov 19-1998 Apr 14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Black, Sarah
    See: Smith College
  - Bloomsbury Workshop 1988 Mar 10-[1997] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Blunt, Wilifred 1976 Nov 2-Nov 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - *Boyd, Elizabeth French 1976 Apr 13-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - British Institute of Professional Photography 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cadmus, Paul 1984 Dec 23-Dec 27 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carrington, Noel 1987 Dec 10-1998 Apr 13 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cecil, Lord David 1984 Mar 4-1984 Mar 14 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - *Charleston Trust 1984 Jun 16-[1992] Jan 11 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - *Chatto & Windus 1979 Aug 13-1988 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clements, Keith 1984 Jul 20-1985 Apr 18 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - *Condé Nast Publications, Inc. 1983 Mar 12-1987 Jul 18 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Contemporary Art Society (London) 1985 Feb 22-1985 Mar 12 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Darroch, Sandra Jobson 1976 Feb 2-1988 Nov 30 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Delaney, Paul 1987 Oct 10-1987 Dec 30 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Diamand, Pamela 1976 Sep 11-Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Emery, Jane 1991 Nov 13-Dec 11 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Florence, Barbara Moench [1984 Dec 14]-1985 Dec 17 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ford, M. A. [1976 Jan ?]-1976 Mar 22 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Freedman, Abby 1994 Apr 19- 1994 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Gallery Edward Harvane 1976 Mar 17-1976 Mar 29 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - *Garnett, Angelica 1976 Aug 14-1988 Jan 2 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Garnett, Henrietta 1988 Jan 23-1988 Jun 24 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Gertler, Luke 1988 Apr 22-1988 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - *Gillespie, Diane F. 1987 Apr 8-1989 Jul 24 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Glendinning, Victoria 1983 Dec 4-1989 Apr 24 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Halls, Michael A. 1987 Oct 12-1987 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - *Harry Ransom Humanities Research Center 1975 Sep 24-1985 Apr 17 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hart-Davis, Rupert 1987 Nov 23-1987 Dec 7 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Harvard University Library 1981 Aug 31-1985 Dec 17 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Haverford College Library 1984 Sep 27-Oct 2 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Heffers Booksellers 1985 Mar 18 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Heilbrun, Caroline G. 1985 Nov 3-1989 Aug 5 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Herley, David 1979 Jul 17 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Hershkowitz, Robert 1985 Mar 19-1985 Mar 31 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Hill, Brian 1989 Jun 17 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Hirschl & Adler Galleries 1989 Jun 10-1989 Jun 15 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - House of El Dieff, Inc. 1982 Nov 18- 1982 Dec 6 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Hussey, Mark 1996 Jul 22- 1996 Jul 30 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Hutchinson, Lord Jeremy 1985 June 7-1985 Jun 17 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - International Museum of Photography at George Eastman House 1985 Sep 22, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - J. Paul Getty Museum 1987 Mar 24-1987 Apr 6 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Kennedy, Richard 1987 Dec 18-1988 Feb 2 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Keynes, Milo 1984 Oct 12-1986 Apr 13 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - *Kirkpatrick, B.J. 1961 Feb 6-1993 Mar 23 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln 1984 Sep 24 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Laing, Donald A. 1983 Oct 16-1983 Dec 12 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Lilly Library 1983 Jan 8-1983 Jan 10 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Lee, Hermione 1996 Nov 5-1996 Jun 12 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Lehmann, John 1977 Jan 6- 1977 Jan 15 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Lewis, R.W.B. 1976 Jul 14-1984 Oct 11 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Mandel, Ann S. 1985 Apr 15-1989 Aug 21 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Mansell Collection 1987 Jul 9-1987 Jul 14 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - McNellie, Andrew 1993 Mar 23-1993 Apr 12 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Meisel, Perry 1985 Dec 16-1985 Dec 19 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art 1989 Jun 5-1989 Jun 16 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Moggridge, D. E. 1984 Oct 20-1984 Dec 22 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Moore, Timothy 1988 Jul 10-1988 Jul 18 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Morris Gallery 1984 Sept 12-1985 Jan 12 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Mortimer, Ruth
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston 1977 Jul 8-1978 Sep 30 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - *National Portrait Gallery (Great Britain) 1983 Feb 21-1997 Nov 7 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - National Trust for Places of Historic Interest 1984 Oct 11-1986 Jan 7 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - New York Public Library
    See: Berg Collection.
  - The New York Times Book Review 1976 Jan 10 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Nicolson, Nigel 1979 Jun 22-1988 Aug 22 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Norton, Lucy [1976 Sep] 2-1976 Oct 17 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Paige, Phyllis C.
  - Partridge, Frances 1984 Dec 26-1985 Oct 29 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Perlin, Bernard 1984 Dec 28-1985 Jan 8 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Peters, Jean 1984 Mar 5-1984 Apr 12 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Photo Researchers, Inc. 1985 Jan 11-1985 Jan 18 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Pierpoint Morgan Library 1981 Jun 11 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Pugh, Patricia 1987 Jul 17-1987 Oct 26 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Quick Jonathan R. 1987 Sep 12-1987 Sep 17 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Reed, Christopher [1987] Aug 8-1996 Jul 24 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Regan, Tom 1988 Jun 14-1988 Jul 4 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - *Reid, Panthea (from and to) 1994 Jul 30-1997 Jan 26 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Ritchie, Trekkie 1989 Aug 22-1992 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Roche, Paul 1989 Oct 30-1989 Nov 28 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - *Rosenbaum, S. P. 1976 Jul 13-1994 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Royal Pavillion Art Gallery, and Museum 1990 Jan 19-1990 Mar 17 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Russell, John 1984 Oct 12-1984 Oct 28 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Rylands, George 1984 Aug 14-1984 Aug 25 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Scott, Alison
  - *Shone, Richard 1981 Jun 3-1994 Mar 8 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Smith, Warren Hunting 1984 May 7-1985 Jan 10 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - *Smith College 1982 Sep 3-1989 Oct 9 (Box 3, Folder 96-97)
  - Sotheby & Co. 1983 May 18-1985 Jan 23 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Southampton Art Gallery 1989 Jul 20-1989 Sep 6 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - *Spotts, Frederic 1986 Nov 15-1997 Jan 22 (Box 3, Folder 100-01)
  - Stansky, Peter [1985] Sep 30-[1985 Oct] (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Stone, Wilfred Healey 1976 Oct 17-1976 Nov 6 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - *Strachey, Barbara (from and to) 1980 Nov 10-1989 Jun 1 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Strachey, Simonette 1985 Dec 17-1986 Jan 23 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - St. Paul's Bibliographies 1987 Oct 26-1990 May 22 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Taylor, Roger 1987 Aug 4-1987 Aug 8 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Temple University 1989 Apr 26 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Turnbaugh, Douglas Blair [1988]-1989 Aug 2 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - University of Leeds 1989 May 25-1989 Sep 2 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - University of California 1984 Jun 1-1984 Jun 13 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - University of Hull 1990 Jan 19-1990 Feb 19 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - University of Reading 1985 Jan 1-1989 Sep 15 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - University of Sussex 1984 May 13-1997 Oct 1 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Vassar College Art Gallery 1985 Jan 12-1985 Mar 19 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Vaughan, Janet 1985 Dec 16-1985 Dec 31 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Victoria and Albert Museum 1983 Apr 12-1985 Feb 25 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Victoria University (Toronto) Library 1984 Oct 20-1984 Nov 1 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Vinogradoff, Julian 1976 Dec 30-[1983 Aug 15] (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Whaley, Charles E. 1984 Jun 25-1984 Jul 20 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Willis, J. H. 1984 Oct 8-1984 Nov 7 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Wolf, Ina 1981 Mar 22-1987 Dec 21 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Wolf, Sylvia 1996 Dec 20-1996 Dec 27 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - *Woolmer, J. Howard (from and to) 1976 Sep 12-1998 Apr 28 (Box 4, Folder 124-6)
  - Unidentified 1976 Mar 15-[1996 Jul] (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Permission letters requesting use of quotations in A Bloomsbury Iconography 1985 Jan 13- 1989 Jan 19 (Box 4, Folder 128)
- Series II. Scrapbooks, 1905-1998
  - (scrapbook 1.1- scrapbook 1.5) (Box 5-9)
    Articles and reviews of works by and about Virginia Woolf.
  - (scrapbook 2) (Box 10)
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    Background articles and extracts about the Bloomsbury Group.
  - (scrapbook 3.1- scrapbook 3.2) (Box 11-12)
    Arranged alphabetically by sitter or artist.
    Reproductions of Bloomsbury-related photographs and artwork.
  - (scrapbook 4) (Box 13)
    Catalogues of Vanessa Bell's exhibitions.
  - (scrapbook 5) (Box 14)
    Catalogues of Duncan Grant's exhibitions.
  - (scrapbook 6.1- scrapbook 6.4) (Box 15-18)
    Miscellaneous exhibition catalogues, 1912-1987. Catalogues of exhibitions and auctions, as well as newspaper articles about openings.
  - (scrapbook 7) (Box 19)
    Arranged alphabetically by publication or author.
    Extracts from reviews containing reproductions of Bloomsbury images.
  - (scrapbook 8) (Box 20)
    Arranged alphabetically by author, sitter, or artist.
    Dust jackets, letters, and lists of illustrations in books.
  - (scrapbook 9.1-9.8) (Box 21-28)
    Bloomsbury 1919-1998. Includes reviews of books and movies about Bloomsbury, obituaries, sales announcements, cartoons, and exhibition reviews.
  - (scrapbook 10) (Box 29)
    Articles about Julia Margaret Cameron. Extra notebook contains photocopies from Victorian Pictures of Famous Men and Fair Women.
  - (scrapbook 11) (Box 30)
    Notes and comments by Elizabeth P. Richardson about her collection.
  - (scrapbook 13) (Box 31)
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    Indexes prepared by Elizabeth P. Richardson of Bloomsbury-related books.
  - (scrapbook 14) (Box 32)
    Ephemera. Includes programs, fliers, and brochures for Bloomsbury related sites and events.
- Series III. Personal Papers, 1963-1998
  - Reading Notebook 1. Reading notes on Virginia Woolf's life and works 1963-1965, 91 pages. (Box 33, Folder 129)
  - Reading Notebook 2. Reading notes on Bloomsbury-related images 1983-1984, 59 pages. (Box 33, Folder 130)
  - Reading Notebook 3. Reading notes on Virginia Woolf and Bloomsbury-related material 1984-1986, 61 pages. (Box 33, Folder 131)
  - Reading Notebook 4. Reading notes on Virginia Woolf's essays and Bloomsbury-related books 1987-1996, 75 pages. (Box 33, Folder 132)
  - Notebook A. Contains drafts and notes on the Iconography, as well as the addresses of people knowledgeable about Bloomsbury., 45 pages. (Box 33, Folder 133)
  - Notebook B. Contains notes on Bloomsbury-related books, mostly concerning photographs ?1983 (Box 33, Folder 134)
  - Notes and sketches of photographs of Lydia Lopokova., 11 pages. (Box 34, Folder 134)
  - Notes on the dating and identifying of the Beresford photographs of Virginia Woolf., 9 pages. (Box 34, Folder 136)
  - Stationery featuring reproduction of a photograph of Virginia Woolf by Beresford. (Box 34, Folder 137)
  - "Bloomsbury Squares" cartoon. photocopy 1980 Dec 8, 1 page. (Box 34, Folder 138)
  - Reproductions of photographs in the Leslie Stephen album, with captions by Elizabeth P. Richardson ?1985 (Box 34, Folder 139)
  - Pattle family trees 1985
    See: Oversize
  - Map of Sussex, England
  - Masterworks of American Painting and Sculpture: typescript, corrected by EPR 1998 (Box 34, Folder 140)
  - Drafts of essays for Smith College class taught by Professor Doug Patey typescript, corrected 1993 Feb 23-Mar 11 (Box 34, Folder 141)
    Includes: The Urkheim Mile And Other Blessings of a Hands-Off Technology and Some Uses and Abuses of the En Dash.
  - Drafts for a review of Leonard Woolf: A Bibliography by Leila Luedeking and Michael Edmonds: typescript, corrected 1993 (Box 34, Folder 142)
  - Budget of Elizabeth P. Richardson for 1992 and 1993. (Box 34, Folder 143)
  - Map of Elizabeth P. Richardson's library. (Box 34, Folder 144)
  - Notebook on the Ribblesdale Lear, a copy of Edward Lear's Book of Nonsense owned by Thomas Lister, 4th Baron Ribblesdale. Research on guests of the family who colored and signed it. n.y. Mar 24, 166 pages. (Box 35, Folder 145)
  - Notes on Edward Lear cartoons from the Ribblesdale Lear, 65 pages (notecards). (Box 35, Folder 146)
  - Notes on the Ribbldale Lear Scrapbook: typescript, corrected. (Box 35, Folder 147)
  - The Ribblesdale Lear Scrapbook 1993 (Box 36)
  - Audio recording of Elizabeth P. Richardson reading Virginia Woolf's Moments of Being., 8 audiocassettes. (Box 37)
  - "A taste for green olives." Elizabeth P. Richardson discusses her Bloomsbury collection. On reverse, Richardson reads Julia Margaret Cameron by Virginia Woolf., audiocassette. 3 copies. (Box 38)
- Series IV. Subject Files, 1865-1997
  - "Architectural Review." May 1930, pages 287-300. photocopy.
  - Bicknell, John W. "Leslie Stephen: Victorian Man of Letters" lecture at Drew University. Introduced by Noel Annan. 1996, Audio recording, 2 copies. (Box 39, Folder 148)
  - Byre, John. "Faulty Connections." A review of Julian Symonds: A bibliography by John J. Walsdorf with Bonnie J. Allen. Times Literary Supplement 1997 Apr 11, page 33. (Box 39, Folder 149)
  - Cannan, Gilbert. Pugs and Peacocks. London: Hutchinson & Co., 312 pages. photocopy. (Box 39, Folder 150)
  - Charleston Trust. Sale catalogue for an auction to benefit the Charleston Trust., photocopy. (Box 39, Folder 151)
  - Cragg, Steven. T-shirt featuring a caricature of Virginia Woolf. Chapel Hill, North Carolina: Largely Literary Designs 1992 (Box 39, Folder 152)
  - Ellenberger, Nancy W. "The Souls and London "Society" at the End of the Nineteenth Century." Victorian Studies Winter 1982, pages 133-168. photocopy. (Box 39, Folder 153)
  - Hafley, James. The Glass Roof: Virginia Woolf as Novelist. Berkeley and Los Angeles: University of California Press 1954, 195 pages. (Box 39, Folder 154)
  - Higgens, Diana. Grace at Charleston: Memories and Recipes. Lockholt & Company Limited. With foreword by Quentin Bell. (Box 40, Folder 155)
  - Mozley, Anita Ventura, Mrs. Cameron's Photographs from the Life. Stanford University Museum of Art 1974, 74 pages. photocopy. (Box 40, Folder 156)
  - Nicolson, Nigel. Sissinghurst Castle: An Illustrated Guide. Bedford: The Sidney Press Limited 1966, 13 pages. photocopy. (Box 40, Folder 157)
  - Reed, Chris. Checklist of illustrations of Bloomsbury art 1986, 22 pages. (Box 40, Folder 158)
  - Ross, Robert. Masques & Phases. London: Arthur L. Humphreys 1909, 315 pages. Photocopy, with Richardson's index. (Box 40, Folder 159)
  - Shone, Richard. Monk's House: A Catalogue of Pictures 1985, 24 pages. (Box 40, Folder 160)
  - Southeby's Belgravia. Early Photographic Images and Related Material. catalogue for auction held 1975 26 Jun, 75 pages. photocopy. (Box 41, Folder 161)
  - Stansky, Peter, On Or About December 1910: Early Bloomsbury and Its Intime World." Introduction." Cambridge: Harvard University Press 1996, photocopy. (Box 41, Folder 162)
  - Stephen, Leslie. The "Times" on the American War. London: William Ridgeway 1865, 108 pages. photocopy. (Box 41, Folder 163)